{
    "id": "7505d90352aa457db9ae7b2c93433bfb",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If he …………………, we will be shocked.",
            "description": "When the verb in the if clause is in the simple present tense, we use will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "loses",
                "lost",
                "had lost"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had known, I ………………. you straightaway.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "would tell",
                "would have told",
                "will tell"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "..................... seen such a mess.",
            "description": "When the sentence begins with a negative expression, the auxiliary verb goes before the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "Seldom I have",
                "Seldom have I"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ..................... tea in the morning.",
            "description": "The adverb goes before the main verb.",
            "answers": [
                "usually drink",
                "drink usually"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………. us.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "visits often",
                "often visits"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind my ………………… the window?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "opening",
                "open",
                "to open"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You …………………. to find the time to do all the things you want to.",
            "description": "Ought is the only modal followed by a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "ought",
                "should",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you don’t want to go, you ………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can't",
                "needn't",
                "mustn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You needn’t …………………. it.",
            "description": "When need is used as a modal auxiliary, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to have done",
                "have done"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you asked more politely, I ............................ you some money.",
            "description": "When the verb in the if-clause is in the simple past tense, we use would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will lend",
                "would lend",
                "would have lent"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}